Guide to the Barb Wiley Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Barb Wiley papers
1990-2005
1990-1997
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5682
Wiley, Barbara$q(Barbara Beth),$d1967-
Records covering 15 years of activism aimed at unionization of child care workers in order to secure better wages and working conditions.
Barb Wiley is a childcare worker and an organizer in the Seattle Worthy Wage campaign. She served on the Seattle Worthy Wages Task Force steering committee from the time of its start (1990). The Worthy Wage Task Force was coordinated by the National Center for the Early Childhood Work Force. until 1999. The national campaign, originally intended to last five years, was initiated to draw attention to the importance of child care work and the urgent need to improve compensation and training for child care workers. The campaign was highly successful in creating a network of individuals, advocates, parents. The locally-based campaigns such as the Seattle Worthy Wages Task Force provided resources and technical support, offered leadership training opportunities, and organized an annual retreat. Funding was obtained primarily through grants. Barb Wiley served as principal contact for many of these grants.
Organized into 2 accessions.
Accession No. 5682-001, Barb Wiley Seattle Worthy Wage Campaign papers, 1990-2005
Accession No. 5682-002, Barbara Wiley papers, 1990-2000
Grant files; reports and publications regarding childcare; program files regarding workships and activities; historical information regarding the Seattle Worthy Wage Task Force. Pamphlets, surveys, focus group papers, mailing lists, and other materials related to the organization of a child care union.
Open to all users.
Wiley, Barbara$q(Barbara Beth),$d1967- $vArchives; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington)
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Washington (State); Seattle
- Barb Wiley Seattle Worthy Wage Campaign papers, 1990-2005; 1990-1997; 5682-001; 2 cubic feet 2 boxes
  Grant files; reports and publications regarding childcare; program files regarding workships and activities; historical information regarding the Seattle Worthy Wage Task Force.
  Open to all users.
- Barbara Wiley papers, 1990-2000; 5682-002; 1.58 cubic feet 2 boxes
  Pamphlets, surveys, focus group papers, mailing lists, and other materials related to the organization of a child care union.
  Barbara "Barb" Wiley, 01/24/2012.
  - Seattle Child Care Standards Project - Survey, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 1/1-5)
  - Mailing Lists, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Consensus Standards - Promotional Materials, 1992 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - King County Child Care Staffing Coalition, 1991 (Box-folder 1/8-10)
  - King County Child Care Staffing Coalition - Meeting, 1992 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - The Child Care Summit - Workshop Evaluation Forms, circa 1991 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - September - Coalition, circa 1991 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Focus Groups
    - Handouts, circa 1990-1991 (Box-folder 1/14-15)
    - Rainbow Packets, circa 1991 (Box-folder 1/16-18)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 1/19-20)
  - T.E.A.C.H. Early Childhood, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 1/21)
  - Worthy Wages Signs for Stuffed Babies, undated (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Center for the Child Care Workforce - National, 1992-2000 (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Child Care Legislation/Policy, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Childcare Union Project, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Miscellaneous Organizing and Campaign, circa 1990-2000 (Box 2)